Starring in Her First Movie!
Barbie in the Nutcracker is a animation, family film directed by Owen Hurley.
The Mouse King casts an evil spell over Clara that causes her to shrink.
Clara and the Nutcracker set out on an adventurous journey to find
Sugarplum Princess, who has the power to undo the spell.
Barbie / Clara (voice), played by Kelly Sheridan.
Nutcracker / Prince Eric (voice), played by Kirby Morrow.
Mouse King (voice), played by Tim Curry.
Pimm (voice), played by Peter Kelamis.
Major Mint (voice), played by Christopher Gaze.
Captain Candy (voice), played by Ian James Corlett.
Barbie in the Nutcracker is a 2001 animated fantasy film co-produced by Mainframe
Entertainment and Mattel Entertainment, and distributed by Artisan Home Entertainment.
Loosely adapted from E.
Hoffmann's 1816 short story, "The Nutcracker and the Mouse King", and featuring music based from Tchaikovsky's 1892 ballet, The Nutcracker, it marked the character's first film since the
1987 television specials; Barbie and the Rockers: Out of This World and Barbie and the Sensations: Rockin' Back to Earth, with Kelly Sheridan providing the voice of Barbie.
It was also the first Barbie movie to be computer-animated.
Barbie in the Nutcracker premiered on VHS on October 2, 2001, by Artisan,
followed up with a DVD release a few weeks later on October 23.
before being subsequently released overseas through
Entertainment Rights and Universal Pictures Video.
The film sold more than 3.4 million units on DVD by 2002,
and grossed $150 million in total sales.
It won the Video Premiere Award for Best Animated Video Premiere Movie.
The film explores themes of magic, mouse, musical, ballet, based on toy.